# 哈喽 大家好 今天我们拍一个不做菜的视频
Hi everyone! Today's video won't be about cooking
# 拍一个测试油温的一个视频
We're shooting a video about testing oil temperature
# 这个是我们准备的豆腐 有鱼有茄子
Here we've prepared tofu, fish, and eggplant
# 四伯爷 那你晓得啥子油温炒啥子菜不哦
Si Boye, do you know about oil temperature in cooking?
# 我清不到你啥子油温炒啥子菜
I'm not sure how you decide on oil temperature when you cook
# 我就是管你对不对 反正在锅里烧热就可以煎
I don't know much other than heating up the wok before we start pan-frying
# 假如这个茄子哈如果是低油温下去的话是不是要吸很多油
If we add this eggplant when the temperature is low, it'll need more oil
# 嗯
Yes
# 我伯爷都知道这个低油温下锅茄子是百分百吸油的
See, my uncle knows that adding eggplant with low temperature would need more oil
# 它会把这个吸得很饱满
It'll absorb a lot of oil
# 然后高油温下去它是在往外面排斥
If it's high temperature, the eggplant actually repels the oil
# 所以我们炒茄子用高油温一直炒的话它不会吸油
So if we stir-fry it with high temperature, it'll keep the oil out
# 然后就是我们这个鱼 还有这个鱼
Then look at this fish, and this
# 鱼下锅煎的话一定要高油温一下子把鱼皮给它煎熟
If you pan-fry the fish, you need high temperature to immediately get the fish skin ready
# 如果慢慢煎很大概率会粘锅
If you pan-fry for a long time, it's likely that it'll burn
# 第一个是粘锅 第二个是容易把鱼煎烂
First it'll stick on the pot, secondly the fish is likely going to fall apart
# 不管是煎草鱼鲤鱼还是鲫鱼
No matter which type of fish it is
# 都要用高油温来煎
You need high oil temperature
# 等会我们煎点豆腐给你看一下嘛
Now let's pan-fry some tofu and show you this
# 要的啊
Go ahead
# 给你做个示范打个样
Show you an example
# 好 那我们现在就到锅上面去操作这个东西
Ok, now we move to the wok for the next step
# 给你们看一下
To show you
# 好 现在我们来简单用一个低油温来炸一个花生米
Cool, now we show a simple trick of frying peanuts with low temperature
# 先倒油
First pour theo il
# 这个是我们准备的花生米
These are the peanuts we prepared
# 直接下锅
Add it to the wok immediately
# 四伯爷 你晓得花生米为什么要冷油下锅去炸不
Si Boye, do you know why we add it before the oil heats up?
# 拿下去炸它才炸得泡撒
If you fry it now, it'll become puffy
# 如果是高油温安
If it's high temperature
# 高油温不得行
That won't work
# 不得行嘎
Won't work
# 高油温要炸糊
It'll burn
# 嗯 然后中间还是生的
Yes, and the middle part would still be raw
# 嗯 对对对
Yep yep
# 我们炸这个花生米就是冷油下去随着油温的加热
When we fry the peanuts, we add it when the oil is cold and as it heats up,
# 花生米中间也开始热
the peanuts heat up from the middle too
# 如果这个花生米你在锅里拿出来吃已经可以了
If you taste it and it's almost done
# 拿出来放一会儿它自己会熟
You can take it all and let it rest
# 所以我们像类似炸这个核桃啊花生米啊腰果呀这些
So frying walnuts, peanuts, and cashew nuts are all the same
# 必须用低油温下锅
You need to add it at low temperature
# 好 现在这个油温大概已经升到了5成
Ok now the oil has increased to 50%
# 我们转中小火保持这个油温
We turn to medium low heat to keep it that way
# 然后炸这个花生米就是我们很典型的
See frying the peanuts is very representative
# 3成油温左右就下花生米
You add it at 30% temperature
# 或者是冷油直接下都可以
Or even when it's cold
# 千万不要把油温烧得太热了
Don't over heat it
# 油温的话每一成30度
The temperature transltates to 30 degrees for every 10%
# 那我们经常能够用得到就是4成5成6成7成就可以了
So what we usually use is 40% to 70%
# 34567
3, 4, 5, 6, 7
# 好像可以了
It's ready
# 那我们现在来煎一个豆腐
Then now we pan-fry some tofu
# 现在是属于一个高油温
Now we have high heat
# 大概是6成油温下的豆腐
We add the tofu at around 60%
# 我们油温高一点的话这个豆腐不会煎烂
If the temperature is high, tofu won't fall apart
# 你看 这样子翻都没事
See, you can even flip it like this
# 看到没有四伯爷
See that, Si Boye?
# 油温高它下去表面马上就有一层金黄金黄的
When the temperature is high, you immediately see it turns golden
# 好 我们把这块拿出来
Ok, now we take it out
# 然后下一个试一下低油温
Then add another to try low temperature
# 我们这个是低油温下去煎
Now we pan-fry at low temperature
# 这个豆腐现在是低油温
Now the tofu is at low temperature
# 如果说油温比较低的情况下我们去翻它
If we flip it now
# 看到没就烂了
See, it breaks apart
# 这个时候就烂了
It breaks just now
# 所以这里我们做一个实验就可以看得出来这个豆腐
So we've done this experiment and we can see that the tofu
# 低油温煎 像这样子没有煎出锅巴出来
When fried at low temperature, wouldn't form the golden layer
# 没有煎出黄黄的东西出来豆腐非常容易碎
Without the golden layer, it tends to fall apart
# 而且还粘勺子
And stick on our utensil
# 好 我们把它拿出来
Ok, let's take it out
# 下一个我们油温稍微高一点来煎鱼
Next we'll pan-fry the fish at slightly higher temperature
# 好 油冒烟了 6成热了
Ok some smoke is coming out, we're at 60%
# 我们大家记住了这个时候鱼不能动
Remember you can't touch the fish now
# 一动它的话它的皮就会烂掉
If you touch it, the skin will break apart
# OK 现在我们给它翻过来
Ok, now we flip it
# 它的鱼皮有可能会表面的那一层皮有可能会烂掉
The fish skin (the first layer) might fall apart
# 但是它的肉是不可能会烂的
But the meat won't
# 我现在翻过来给大家看一下
Now we flip it to take a look
# 大家可以看一下
You can see
# 煎得金黄金黄的
It's golden
# 这一面就没有怎么烂
This side didn't break
# 然后我们接着煎
We continue to pan-fry
# OK 我们这个鱼可以看得到
Ok, we can see
# 煎得比较脆 表皮比较脆
the fish is quite crispy, the surface
# 然后是没有烂的 这个形状保持的比较好
And it hasn't fall apart, it's in good shape
# 我们下面一个来低油温试一下
Now we try it with low temperature
# 这一次油温就稍微低一些
Now the temperature is slightly lower
# 油温低的情况下 我们煎完了翻过来看一下
With low temperature, we flip it after a while
# 大家可以看一下 鱼肉它这里烂了
You can see how the meat is falling apart
# 鱼肉已经烂了
It's fallen apart
# 再看一下另外一面
Now look at the other side
# 这边肉也在开始烂 而且也同样的粘勺子
This side too, and it's also sticky
# 现在我拿刚才高油温煎的这条鱼来对比一下
Now compare it with the fish that's pan-fried with high temperature
# 我们可以对比一下
Let's compare
# 油温低的这条已经爆开了 肉它慢慢的会爆开
This one under low temperature has fallen apart gradually
# 然后高油温下去马上煎定型的这个金黄金黄的
The other one that immediately formed shape in high temperature is golden
# 这个皮也没怎么烂 肉也不会爆
And its skin and meat aren't apart
# 大家可以看一下
You can take a look
# 鱼比较完整 这条已经烂了
This fish looks good, the other not great
# 已经碎了这个肉
Its meat has come apart
# 可以看一下这边
Look at this side
# 这边也碎了
It's not held together
# 好 下一个我们来试一下低油温茄子
Ok next we'll try eggplants in low temperature
# 我们现在这个油温大概是不到100℃
Now the temperature is probably below 100 degrees
# 现在下茄子试一下
Now add the eggplant and try
# 好 其实这个已经差不多够了
Ok, actually this is enough
# 四伯爷你看这个茄子
Si Boye, look at the eggplant
# 看到没这个里面好多油
See, a lot of oil
# 是安
Yeah
# 我现在用这个勺子能够挤出油来
We can see the oil come out if we press it
# 所以我们茄子下锅油温低了直接就吸油
So if we add the eggplant at low temperature, it immediately absorbs the oil
# 跟海绵一样把油都吸走了
Like a sponge
# 现在我来试一下高油温
Now let's test with high temperature
# 好 现在油温烧到了六七成了
Ok, now it's reaching 60% or 70%
# 同样下茄子
We also add eggplants
# 大家可以看一下 这样的茄子它是没有吸油
As you can see, the eggplant doesn't absorb the oil
# 它的泡泡是不停的往外面冒
You see the bubbles coming out
# 你看我们的油温稍微高一点下去
See if we add it when the temperature is a bit higher
# 它这个茄子直接炸得金黄金黄的
It immediately turns golden
# 我们现在捞出来看一下
Let's take it out to take a look
# 好 我现在关火
Ok, I'm turning off the stove
# 我们看一下2个茄子同样的都是炸
Let's look at the two eggplants, both fried
# 这一个里面吸得油很多
This has lots of oil
# 这个也吸了油但是没有这个这么多
The other too, but not as much
# 这个里面炸出来的茄子中间是很嫩的
This one is soft in the middle
# 这个吃起来的话中间是很老的
The other one is not
# 所以我们茄子下锅不拍淀粉的情况下
So if we don't cover it with corn starch
# 高油温下去一下子就把它的水份逼出来
High temperature will let the water out immediately
# 不让它（有）吸油的机会
So that it doesn't absorb the oil
# 如果是说不喜欢吃油腻的给它拍层淀粉下去
If you don't like the greasy taste, add some starch
# 它阻断了茄子吸油的这个面
It prevents the eggplant from absorbing from the surroundings
# 本期视频就简单的说到这里
This is the end of today's video
# 然后大家如果感兴趣的话
If you're interested
# 以后我会做一期更加详细
I'll make another one to explain in more details
# 涉及到3成4成5成6成7成8成油温
About temperatures ranging from 30% to 80%
# 这是我们炒菜经常能够用到的油温
Which are the ones we usually use when cooking
# 下次再跟你们分享更完整的视频
I'll see you again in our next video
# 本期视频就到这里了 拜拜
See you!